Susan Caperna Lloyd collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Mexico
  - Subseries 2: Zapatistas
    - Portfolio 8: Emiliano Zapata: Mexican Folk Hero, 1992-1996, Emiliano Zapata, born of a peasant family in Anenecuilco, Mexico in 1879, was the southern leader of the Mexican Revolution (1910-1920). Joining forces with Pancho Villa, he led a movement to regain lands expropriated by colonial land
      - Print 9: (Left to right) Roberto and Jorge Zapata, great-grandchildren of Emiliano Zapata, in doorway of Emiliano Zapata's General Headquarters, Tlatizapan de Zapata, Morelos, Mexico, April 1992, The General Headquarters is a building used during the 1910-1920 Mexican Revolution. AFC 2018/064: SL-18-06.
      - Print 10: Masked Zapatistas in front of mural depicting Che Guevara, folk hero, Oventic, Chiapas, Mexico, New Year's Day, January 1, 1996, Zapatistas gathered in Oventic to celebrate the first anniversary of the 1994 Zapatista uprising, a movement invoking Zapata's name to regain lands never restored sufficiently after the 1910-1920 Mexican Revolution. For more information about the first anniversary of the Chiapas Zapatista uprising see AFC 2018/064: G-38; for additional information about ongoing Chiapas uprising see also AFC 2018/064: G-41; AFC 2018/064: G-42; and AFC 2018/064: G-43. See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-06.
      - Print 11: Masked Zapatista at first anniversary of 1994 Zapatista uprising, Oventic, Chiapas, Mexico, New Year's Day, January 1, 1996, See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-06.
      - Print 12: Masked Zapatista family at first anniversary of 1994 uprising, Oventic, Chiapas, Mexico, New Year's Day, January 1, 1996, See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-02.
      - Print 13: Auditorium set up for first anniversary of 1994 Zapatista uprising, Oventic, Chiapas, Mexico, New Year's Day, January 1, 1996, Banner text in photo: "Votan Zapata guardian y corazón del pueblo para todos todo nada para nosotros" (Zapata, guardian and heart of the pueblo). In reference to Zapata, Votan is a legendary or mythological figure mentioned in early European accounts of the Maya civilization). See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-05.
      - Print 14: Zapatistas painting mural for the first anniversary of 1994 Zapatista uprising, Oventic, Chiapas, Mexico, December 31, 1995, See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-06.
      - Print 15: Satirical wall cartoon and slogan illustrating Zapata's ideals about land ownership, Tepoztlán, Morelos, Mexico, January 5, 1996, The political cartoon, painted as a wall mural, illustrates developers who want to buy indigenous lands. The balloon quotes Zapata, which translates as "the earth belongs to those who work it." From my notes in conversation with Martin Balderrama, a Tepoztlán resident: "The former mayor promised that in Tepoztlán he would defend the land. But he didn't live up to his promise. He, with his friends in the municipal government, made clandestine arrangements with Grupo KS to accept the construction of the golf course project." See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-03.
      - Print 16: Zapata wall mural, Zihuatenejo, Guerrero, Mexico, 1992, See negatives AFC 2018/064: SL-18-08.
    - Interview of Emeterio Pantaleon, veteran of 1910-1920 Mexican Revolution, 1994, AFC 2018/064: SR015; 1 sound cassette
    - Mexican folk music (corridos) of 1910-1920 Mexican Revolution, 1994, AFC 2018/064: MV131; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Susan Lloyd Wisconsin Public Radio interview about Mexican folk hero, Emiliano Zapata, 1994, AFC 2018/064: SR017; 1 sound cassette
    - Voice of Emeterio Pantaleon, veteran of 1910-1920 Mexican Revolution, 1994, AFC 2018/064: SR020; 1 sound cassette
    - Zapatista interviews, Morelos, Mexico, 1994, AFC 2018/064: SR016; 1 sound cassette
    - [ The Last Zapatista ], 1994, Manuscripts and ephemera from The Last Zapatista film creation and showing.; 1 folder (Box/folder 25/2)
    - Audiovisual materials related to the film The Last Zapatista (1995), 1994-1997, 2018, The Last Zapatista is a thirty minute documentary by Susan Lloyd about Emiliano Zapata, the leader of the 1910-1920 Mexican Revolution, and the persistent folk legends still surrounding him in Mexico today.
      - Camera original element, January 1994, AFC 2018/064: MV090-MV101; Footage shot in Mexico by Cal Kennedy (Medford, Oregon). Footage centered around documentation of Emeterio Pantaleon, veteran who fought with folk hero, Zapata.; Cal Kennedy; 12 videocassettes (Betacam SP)
      - Camera original element, April 1994, AFC 2018/064: MV102-MV118; Footage shot in Mexico by Kevin Peer (Asheville, North Carolina). Footage centered around Emeterio Pantaleon, Morelos campesinos, anniversary commemorations of Zapata's birth and death, President Salinas de Gortari.; Kevin Peer; 17 videocassettes (Betacam SP)
      - Camera original element, 1994, AFC 2018/064: MV135-MV154; Footage shot in Mexico.; 20 videocassettes (Hi8)
      - Copy of footage of Zapata commemoration, 1994, AFC 2018/064: MV132; Zapata died on April 10, 1919 at the hands of traitors at Chinameca Hacienda in Morelos, Mexico. The commemoration occurs every year on that day in Cuautla, Morelos. Shot by Kevin Peer in Beta SP.; Kevin Peer; 1 videocassette (VHS)
      - Window dub of camera original element, 1994, AFC 2018/064: MV119-MV130; 12 videocassettes (Betacam SP)
      - Master copy, 1995, AFC 2018/064: MV134; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
      - Sub-master copy from 3/4 inch master copy, 1997, AFC 2018/064: MV133; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP)
      - DVD version, 2018, afc2018064_dc005; Made by film distributor, Berkeley Media Berkeley, California.; 6 moving image files (vob, ifo)
    - Susan Lloyd KSOR Radio interview about Mexican folk hero, Emiliano Zapata, 1995, AFC 2018/064: SR019; 1 sound cassette
    - Chiapas, Mexico notebook, 1995-1996, Log of trip to attend first anniversary of Zapatista uprising in Oventic, Chiapas, Mexico. Mayan folklore and cosmology (sketch), traditional clothing with Zapatista masking, arpa (traditional harp music), Zapata legends, connection between Tepoztlán and Chiapas, uprising in Tepoztlán over building of golf course.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 24/6)
    - Susan Lloyd KCSB Radio interview about Mexican folk hero, Emiliano Zapata, February 1996, AFC 2018/064: SR018; 1 sound cassette
    - Mexico Zapatistas, 1996, AFC 2018/064: SL-18-01 – SL-18-08; 189 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-18-01: Emeterio and Shane; 1-25, 11A, 15A, 19A, 23A, scanned 1/31/2019; SL-18-02: Chiapas; 2-36, Missing 10, 11, 13; SL-18-03: Tepoztlán; 3-27; SL-18-04: Chiapas; 2-26; SL-18-05: Chiapas, Miscellaneous Zapatistas; Missing 6A-11, 21A-26, 31A-35; SL-18-06: Chiapas, Zapatistas at rally, Zapatista wall mural; 6A-11, 2-30A, 32-36A, To scan: #36, #6; SL-18-07: Chiapas; 1-36 complete; SL-18-08: Zapata mural, Guerrero 1992, Mexico; 13-17, To scan: #14.; Kodak 5063; Ilford (Box 22)
    - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-18], 1 folder (Box/folder 37/13)
    - Susan Lloyd lecture at McGill University about Mexican folk hero, Emiliano Zapata, 2001, AFC 2018/064: SR023; Sound only, no picture.; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
- Series 4: Ecuador and Peru
  - Ecuador and Peru notebook, 1977, Photographic documentation of folk art santos, Ecuador and Peru (MFA thesis, University of Oregon). List of santos photographed and churches. Pre-Columbian sites.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 25/3)
  - Andes bus trip/folk markets/Inca stonework, Peru, 1977, AFC 2018/064: PH0641-PH0660; 20 color slides (35 mm); 641, Bus in Andes, on road between Lima and Cuzco; 642, Huancayo, Peruvian Andes; 643, Main plaza; Huancayo; 644, Tourist bartering with Inca Indian in Huancayo market; 645, Inca vendor with traditional weavings, Huancayo market; 646, Incas with baby on back and carrying corn, Huancayo; 647, Textile dyes for sale in Huancayo market; 648, Street children sleep on bench, Cuzco train stop; 649-650, Cross with folk painting and textile wrapping, Cuzco; 651, Inca stone wall without masonry, Hatun Rumiyoc Street, Cuzco; 652, Inca stone with twelve angles, Hatun Rumiyoc Street, Cuzco; 653, Street photographer posing child, Cuzco; 654, Man reading newspaper with parrots, Cuzco; 655, Indian and Inca sacred site, Sacsahuaman, Cuzco; 656-657, Inca boy at Sacsahuaman sacred site, Cuzco; 658, Incas in hats from different villages, Ollantaytambo; 659, Fishing on the Urubamba River, Ollantaytambo; 660, Homes with tin roof near Machu Picchu, Agua Caliente. (Box 4)
  - Machu Picchu/Pisac, Peru, 1977, AFC 2018/064: PH0661-PH0680; 20 color slides (35 mm); 661, Inca sun dial; 662, Sun dial, Pisac; 663, Terraced hillside and Inca women, Pisac; 664, German backpackers ascend stairs, Ollantaytambo Incan ruins; 665, Inca group vending weavings socialize at Pisac ruins; 666, Huayna Picchu, one of two peaks surrounding Machu Picchu; 667, Inca fortification ruins about Pisac; 668, Ancient Inca adobe wall, Pisac; 669, Inca stone masonry, Pisac; 670, Llamas at Machu Picchu; 671, Inca stone stairs into inner chamber; 672, Llama with Huayna Picchu peak; 673, Irrigation system and Inca stonework; 674, Inca terraced hillside; 675, Llamas and tourist mini-buses, Machu Picchu entrance; 676, Inca stone housing area; 677, Inca stone stairway; 678, Llamas at Machu Picchu; 679, Inca stone altar niche; 680, Stone structures and Huayna Picchu peak. (Box 4)
  - Chan Chan, Peru, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-04-01; 4 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Missing 1-5, 13 and up; Negative #11 in Portfolio 1, Print 4.; Agfapan 25 (Box 21)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-04], 1 folder (Box/folder 36/12)
  - Peru, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-05-01 – SL-05-12; 68 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); 18 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-05-01: Plastic Jesus, Cuzco; Missing 4-12, Scanned #3, printed 8/22/18; SL-05-02: Sacsahuman, Cuzco; Missing 1-5, 13-14, 18 and up; SL-05-03: Covered altar, Cuzco; Missing 17 and up; SL-05-04: Ayacucho and Cuzco, Peru; Negative #7 in Portfolio 1, Print 5; SL-05-05: Ayacucho; Missing 14 and up; SL-05-06: Pisac, Peru; SL-05-07: Cuzco, Peru (Pisac); SL-05-08: Cuzco, Peru (Ollantaytambo); SL-05-09: Peru (roofs) Cuzco; SL-05-10: Peru (Sacsahuaman); SL-05-11: Peru (Sacsahuaman); SL-05-12: Peru (Lake Titicaca), Floating island homes.; Agfapan 25; Agfapan 100; Ilford Pan F (Box 21)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-05], 1 folder (Box/folder 36/13)
  - Quito, Ecuador/Otavalo Market, 1978, AFC 2018/064: PH0621-PH0640; 20 color slides (35 mm); 621, School girls in uniforms, Quito; 622, Otavalo Indians in traditional ponchos, Otavalo; 623, Otavalo Indian woman/street vendor/Christo Santo, Quito; 624, Indian girl in traditional woven dress, Otavalo market; 625, Carved folk angel, Quito church; 626, Quito street with pedestrians, trucks, and buses; 627, School children at municipio, Quito; 628, Vendor's child in box of weavings, Otavalo market; 629, Train from Quito to Otavalo market; 630, Otavalo Indian girl in traditional gold beads, Otavalo market; 631, Otavalo Indian girl in gold beads with father, Otavalo market; 632, Otavalo Indian girl with produce, Otavalo market; 633, Otavalo Indian girls with herbs, including nettle, for sale, Otavalo market; 634, Vines and mud from red adobe house, Otavalo; 635, Cactus growing on top of adobe house, Otavalo; 636, Girl and tied up pig, Otavalo; 637, Indian boy in traditional hat sits with clothing bags, Otavalo market; 638-639, Boy sells three minute phone calls, Quito; 640, Parrots and monkeys for sale in Otavalo market. (Box 4)
  - Quito, Ecuador, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-03-01 – SL-03-05; 2 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); 40 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-03-01: Santo with hat, Ecuador; Scanned #1 (long shot), printed #1 9/12/18; SL-03-02: Quito Ecuador street scene with Santo; Scanned 4A 9/22, printed 4A 10/16.; Agfapan 25; Ilford Pan F (Box 21)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-03], 1 folder (Box/folder 36/11)
- Series 5: Southwest United States
  Additional material collected by Lloyd in the Southwest United States, related to Holy Week religious ritual in New Mexico and Arizona, can be found in Series 7.
  - San Xavier Mission, Tucson, Arizona, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-01-01 – SL-01-03; 18 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); SL-01-01: Complete; SL-01-02: San Xavier feet and photo of boy; Scanned #5 and #6 9/12/18, printed #5 and #6 9/12/18; SL-01-03: Negative #11 in Portfolio 1, Print 13.; Ilford FP4; Ilford Pan F (Box 21)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-01], 1 folder (Box/folder 36/9)
  - Chimayó/Trampas, New Mexico, 1980, AFC 2018/064: SL-09-01 – SL-09-04; 23 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); 21 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-09-01: Trampas, New Mexico, Virgin; Complete, Scanned #2 9/14, printed #2 10/17/18; SL-09-02: Chimayó, New Mexico; Complete; SL-09-03: Chimayó Church interior with sky, Pueblo Kiva; Complete thru 21, Need to print, Missing 1-2, 13-36, 10/16/18 scanned 5A and 6A, printed 6A 10/17/18; SL-09-04: Chimayó Church; Missing 10-36.; Ilford FP4; Kodak 6057; Kodak Tri-X 5063 (Box 21)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-09], 1 folder (Box/folder 37/4)
  - New Mexico (1 of 2), 1980-2004, 1 folder (Box/folder 26/1)
    - Feature by Susan Lloyd about search for Halley's Comet in New Mexico desert. Two versions, one in The Oregonian (Portland, Oregon), page B1 and one in Albuquerque Journal Magazine, March-April, 1986, See AFC 2018/064: PH0797-PH0798.; AFC 2018/064: F-01
    - List of Pueblo Indian dance schedule, 1986, See AFC 2018/064: PH0797-PH0798 of San Ildefonso Pueblo.; AFC 2018/064: F-02
    - Letter from Susan Lloyd to Tom Lloyd about Santo Domingo Pueblo Indian dance that she photographed. Postcard from Susan Lloyd to mother-in-law Claire Lloyd when Susan lived in New Mexico with her family. Postcard without stamp or postmark was enclosed in missing larger envelope. Also note to Claire Lloyd, written when Lloyd was writer-in-residence at Wurlitzer Foundation, Taos, New Mexico, 1986, 2004, AFC 2018/064: F-03
    - Magazine article about Ranchos de Taos church, Wall Street Journal, September 30, 1983, See AFC 2018/064: PH0799.; AFC 2018/064: F-04
    - Correspondence between Susan Lloyd and artist, Robert Kostka, her former professor at the University of Oregon and lifelong friend. His connections to New Mexico spurred Lloyd to travel there frequently as artist-in-residence (as was Kostka) at the Wurlitzer Foundation in Taos. Letters include observations of New Mexican folk life such as Pueblo Indian dances, Penitente Holy Week rituals, the landscape, and tourism's effect on folk mores of Hispanic and Indian culture, 1980-2004, For more about New Mexico Holy Week religious rituals see Series 7, Subseries 3.; AFC 2018/064: F-05
    - Story by Susan Lloyd, Westward YoHoHo, Albuquerque Journal Magazine about astrological folklore and mythology sighting Orion when visiting Bandelier National Monument. Also letter from David Owens, Albuquerque Journal graphics editor and Susan's former student at the University of Oregon, 1987, See AFC 2018/064: PH0781-PH0795.; AFC 2018/064: F-06
  - New Mexico (2 of 2), 1980-2004, 1 folder (Box/folder 26/2)
    - Letters from Robert Kostka to Susan Lloyd about Navajo relocation, April 11-May 30, 1986, See England, New Mexico notebook for description of trip to Tees Toh, Arizona to interview Navajos, Pueblo Indian dances, pages 95-193.; AFC 2018/064: F-07
    - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, On Halley's Path, about her search with her young sons for Halley's Comet in New Mexico desert, 1986, AFC 2018/064: F-08
    - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Brothers on Good Friday, about Good Friday crossbearers on the highway and a Penitente ritual at a Talpa morada, New Mexico, 1986, For more about New Mexico Holy Week religious rituals see Series 7, Subseries 3.; AFC 2018/064: F-09
    - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Sailors Have More Fun, about Hopi and Navajo astrological folklore at Bandelier National Monument. Also includes sky astronomical calendar, 1986, See AFC 2018/064: F-06.; AFC 2018/064: F-10
  - Navajo Indians (1 of 2), 1985-1986, 1 folder (Box/folder 26/3)
    - Story by Susan Lloyd about Willie Lone Wolf Scott and the Big Mountain forced Indian relocation, Arizona, Lithiagraph (Ashland, Oregon) Volume 2, Number 5, pages 4-5. Also letter from Willie to Susan Lloyd about Big Mountain struggle against Navajo removal. Willie was member of the American Indian Movement, well-known Navajo activist, and died in 2002, 1985, Picture published is AFC 2018/064: SL-22-02.; AFC 2018/064: D-01
    - Story by Susan Lloyd about Marilyn James and the Big Mountain forced Indian relocation, Arizona, Lithiagraph (Ashland, Oregon) Volume 2, Number 8, page 3, 1985, Picture published is AFC 2018/064: SL-22-03.; AFC 2018/064: D-02
    - Feature article by Susan Lloyd, The Flag at Tees Toh, The Oregonian (Portland, Oregon), page B1, about Cecil Miles and the Big Mountain forced Indian relocation, Arizona, April 27, 1986, Picture published is AFC 2018/064: SL-22-01.; AFC 2018/064: D-03
    - Letter from Louise Benally, a Navajo activist involved with the Big Mountain relocation, giving Susan Lloyd directions to get to Big Mountain, AFC 2018/064: D-04
    - Two letters from Robert Kostka about an article likely published in the Denver Post, and one from the editor of the newspaper. Kostka is from Taos, New Mexico. The article was written by Susan Lloyd, possibly titled Flag at Tees Toh, and is similar to an article in The Oregonian, April 27, 1986, AFC 2018/064: D-05
    - Original manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Flag at Tees Toh, about Navajo Cecil Miles, his World War II service, and the Big Mountain forced Indian relocation, Arizona, 1986, AFC 2018/064: D-06
    - Original manuscript by Susan Lloyd, On the Road with Marilyn James, about meeting with Marilyn as she toured the U.S. to further the Navajo Indian efforts to stop their relocation at Big Mountain, 1985, AFC 2018/064: D-07
    - Letter from Marilyn James to Susan Lloyd with contact information for officials involved in the Big Mountain Navajo relocation dispute. Includes description of fires on the reservation, July 10, 1985, AFC 2018/064: D-08
    - Letter from Willie Lone Wolf to Susan Lloyd describing his solidarity with the Navajo elders at Big Mountain and about his participation in the Sun Dance, July 24, 1985, AFC 2018/064: D-09
  - Navajo Indians (2 of 2), 1985-1986, 1 folder (Box/folder 26/4)
    - Susan Lloyd photo of Willie Lone Wolf, outside sweat lodge with Sun Dance scars on chest, at Ashland, Oregon "Freedom Express" encampment, See AFC 2018/064: SL-22-02.; AFC 2018/064: D-10
    - Newsletter from Northwest Big Mountain Navajo Support with information about tour itineraries and film showings about the Big Mountain Navajo relocation, Portland, Oregon, January 9, 1986, AFC 2018/064: D-11
    - Flyer "Apartheid," with Arizona legislative contact information regarding the Navajo forced relocation referred to as Public Law 93-531, 1985, AFC 2018/064: D-12
    - Two flyers, "Big Mountain Alert" and "Indian Wars 1985-6 in Arizona" about Big Mountain and Peabody Coal Company efforts to procure coal underneath Navajo homes, 1985-1986, AFC 2018/064: D-13
    - Flyer about Udall/McCain Proposal, a compromise bill to resolve Navajo relocation and land issues between Navajo and Hopi Indians, February 27, 1986, AFC 2018/064: D-14
    - Letter from Susan Lloyd to her mother, Gail Caperna, about her journey to Big Mountain, Arizona, the Navajo relocation, experiences with peyote ceremony and World War II Navajo veterans, March 20, 1986, AFC 2018/064: D-15
    - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, South Africa at Big Mountain, comparing Navajo removal to South African apartheid and her experience at a Navajo feast in Tees Toh, Arizona, 1986, AFC 2018/064: D-16
    - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Old Eyes, about Willie Lone Wolf, Navajo activist and leader of anti-relocation movement, See AFC 2018/064: SL-22-02 for portraits of Willie; AFC 2018/064: D-17
  - [Navajo Indians], 1986, Manuscripts and ephemera about Navajo Indians in the American Southwest; 1 folder (Box/folder 26/5)
  - Anasazi pueblo dwellings/U.S. Southwest, 1986, AFC 2018/064: PH0781-PH0800; 20 color slides (35 mm); 781, Navajo home, horses and Shiprock rock formation, Farmington, New Mexico; 782, Horses and Shiprock rock formation, Farmington, New Mexico; 783-784, White House ruins, Canyon de Chelly, Arizona; 785, Pine trees on floor of Frijoles Canyon, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 786, Adobe ruins of pueblo village, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 787-788, Ladder and cave dwellings, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 789, Cave dwellings, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 790-791, Ladder and cave dwellings, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 792-794, The Great Kiva above Frijoles Canyon, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 795, The Great Kiva seen through cave opening, Bandelier National Monument, New Mexico; 796, Tar streaks on modern adobe building, Santa Fe, New Mexico; 797-798, San Ildefonso (active) pueblo, New Mexico; 799, Rancho de Taos (sixteenth century adobe), Taos, New Mexico; 800, Modern adobe building, Taos, New Mexico. (Box 5)
  - Big Mountain Navajos, Marilyn James, Willie Lone Wolf Scott, Cecil Miles, 1986, AFC 2018/064: SL-22-01 – SL-22-03; 45 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); 9 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); SL-22-01: Frame 13 (Cecil Miles - "Flag at TeesToh"), 2-26; SL-22-02: Complete; SL-22-03: Frame 9 Marilyn James "On the Road with Marilyn James."; Kodak (Box 22)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-22], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/2)
  - Cultures of New Mexico, March 2012, afc2018064_dc001; 1-27, Folk mural entitled Las Tres Culturas del Mestizo by Carlos Cervantes in Louis Montano Park on Alta Street in Santa Fe.; 27 still image files (jpg)
- Series 6: France and England
  Additional material collected by Lloyd in France, related to Kali folklore, can be found in Series 16.
  - England, France, Italy notebook, 1978, Notes on pages 8-10, 33-34 about French lesson and visit to a Paris puppet shop which became Pierrots of Paris.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 25/4)
  - Paris, France and marionette shop, 1978, AFC 2018/064: PH0817-PH0820; 4 color slides (35 mm); 817, Pires Francisco stands among versions of Pierrot, French folk marionette, in Paris puppet shop; 818, Couple with luggage waiting for train, Gare du Nord train station; 819, Children create designs with a chair in park near Notre Dame Cathedral; 820, Gothic cathedral of Notre Dame. (Box 5)
  - France, 1978, 1985, 2002, 1 folder (Box/folder 25/5)
    - Pierrots of Paris original typescript by Susan Lloyd, 1985, England, France, and Italy notebook, pages 8-9 for original notes made in Paris, 1978.; AFC 2018/064: N-01
    - Photos by Susan Lloyd in article, Pierrots...a Cameo of Paris in Flying Springbok, pages 72-75, August 1985, AFC 2018/064: PH0817-PH0827.; AFC 2018/064: N-02
    - Production photos of Paris puppet shop used in article, Pierrots...a Cameo of Paris in Flying Springbok magazine, 1978, AFC 2018/064: N-02 and AFC 2018/064: PH0817, PH0825, PH0826, PH0827. Photos taken in 1978. See England, France, and Italy notebook, pages 8-9 for original notes made in Paris, 1978.; AFC 2018/064: N-03
    - Essay by Susan Lloyd, Following in the Path of Patriots in The Sunday Oregonian, about Lloyd's visit to Normandy Beach, June 2, 2002, AFC 2018/064: N-04
    - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Thank You, Vets: D-Day Revisited, about Lloyd's visit to Normandy Beach, 2002, AFC 2018/064: N-05
  - England anti-nuclear movement (1 of 2), 1984-1986, 1 folder (Box/folder 25/6)